<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hypriotos on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/hypriotos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hypriotos on Docker Pirates ARMed with explosive stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/hypriotos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get Docker working on your favourite ARM board with HypriotOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-get-docker-working-on-your-favourite-arm-board-with-hypriotos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/how-to-get-docker-working-on-your-favourite-arm-board-with-hypriotos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all began when Dieter aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Quintus23M&#34;&gt;@Quintus23M&lt;/a&gt; started to experiment with the NVIDIA ShieldTV.
The ShieldTV is a curious little thing. Sold as a media hub for your living room it does deliver one teraflop of processing power.
On top of that it is one of the first 64-bit ARM boards that can be bought for a reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of our blog know that it is not in Dieter&amp;rsquo;s nature to resist the Sirens voices of such an appealing beauty for long.
Read on to learn what happened next&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last December he started the work to get Docker running on the ShieldTV and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.hypriot.com/post/getting-docker-running-on-a-highend-arm-gaming-console-for-fun-and-profit/&#34;&gt;described his journey&lt;/a&gt; on our blog.
The gist of it is that it was quite an involved process of creating his own custom Debian based operating system that supported building Go and Docker for ARM64.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of Dieter on the ShieldTV inspired our team to revisit the way we were building our beloved HypriotOS for the Raspberry Pi.
Longing to publish the way we build it for quite some time we had been ashamed to actually do it because it was such a complicated mess.
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong - it worked well enough and was completely automated with our CI system and even tested, but ultimately it was difficult to understand and change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Dieter&amp;rsquo;s work got us thinking:
What if we could restructure the build process of HypriotOS in such a way that it would be built in distinct layers that would create distinct build artifacts on their own.
What if those artifacts could be tested and published on their own, too? Only to be assembled in a final step at the end to create a fully working SD card image.
What if those distinct steps were self-contained and easy to understand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we had some time at our hands and we started working on a build process that would be the answer to all those questions.
It is certainly still a little rough around the edges and needs further tweaking but it produces a working SD card image for the Raspberry Pi.
We consider it beta quality and it is not yet completely on par with our stable HypriotOS Hector image, but it already runs very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main repository for building HypriotOS SD card image for the Raspberry Pi can be found at GitHub in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-rpi&#34;&gt;Image-Builder-Rpi Repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what happens in this repository?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically it just assembles prepared artifacts into a working SD card image which then can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/flash&#34;&gt;easily flashed&lt;/a&gt; onto a SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artifacts that are combined here are produced elsewhere each in their own GitHub repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/os-rootfs&#34;&gt;a basic filesystem that is based on Debian Jessie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/rpi-kernel&#34;&gt;a Raspberry Pi compatible Linux kernel and firmware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-raw&#34;&gt;a Raspberry Pi image file that contains the necessary partitions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://packagecloud.io/Hypriot/Schatzkiste&#34;&gt;a couple of Debian packages with software like Docker, Docker-Machine and Docker-Compose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea is that all these artifacts can be build and tested with the help of Docker.
For instance if you look into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/os-rootfs&#34;&gt;os-rootfs&lt;/a&gt; repository you will find a &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; in the root of the project that will allow you to create a build and test environment for the root filesystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes two important things possible: Firstly it allows others to build the rootfs locally on their own computer and fix or extend the rootfs with ease.
And secondly the rootfs is build and tested on &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/hypriot/os-rootfs&#34;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; everytime somebody creates - for instance - a pull request.
Combined these two points create a transparent development process with instant feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out that this approach is generic and powerful enough to be applied - you probably already guessed it - to the NVIDIA ShieldTV, too.
By publishing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-nvidia-shieldtv&#34;&gt;Image-Builder-NVIDIA-ShieldTV&lt;/a&gt; repository we are making good on Dieter&amp;rsquo;s promise to publish the sources for Dieter&amp;rsquo;s journey with the ShieldTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hold on - that&amp;rsquo;s not all. To proof to ourselves that this process allows to easily port HypriotOS to different development boards we created &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-odroid-c1&#34;&gt;another Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.
It builds a SD card image for the very capable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hardkernel.com/main/products/prdt_info.php?g_code=G143703355573&#34;&gt;ODROID C1+&lt;/a&gt; development board.
Similar to the Raspberry Pi 2 the ODROID C1+ features a quad core ARMv7 CPU with 1 GB of memory. Distinct from the Raspberry Pi 2 it features a gigabit ethernet port.
A highlevel comparision of both devices can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cnx-software.com/2015/02/02/raspberry-pi-2-odroid-c1-development-boards-comparison/&#34;&gt;CNX-Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this third supported board for HypriotOS we proofed to ourselves that this new build process makes it not only feasible but actually quite easy to extend the support of HypriotOS to new development boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the relation of the different repositories now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/hypriotos-xxx/hypriotos_buildpipeline.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these changes also redefined for us what HypriotOS is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our old mission statement for HypriotOS was:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;HypriotOS is a minimal operating system for the Raspberry Pi 1 &amp;amp; 2 that provides an optimized environment for running Docker. It is very easy to install and use. HypriotOS prides itself for coming with very recent versions of the Linux kernel and all included software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our new mission statement is:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;HypriotOS is a minimal Debian-based operating system for &lt;strong&gt;many popular IoT devices&lt;/strong&gt; that provides an optimized environment for running Docker. It is very easy to install and use. HypriotOS prides itself for coming with very recent versions of the Linux kernel and all included software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is just a small change but it will have big implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest downsides of having an ever increasing amount of IoT devices to choose from is fragmentation. Each device comes with varying support for existing operating systems.
Take Linux for instance. Even if a vendor provides Linux support for a device from the start - it is often based on an outdated Linux kernel.
This in turn often enough means that you can only use old software on top of it. Docker with OverlayFS is such an example. It can only be used with a Linux kernel greater than 3.18.
And that&amp;rsquo;s not only a problem of the small vendors, it even happens with big vendors like NVIDIA. The NVIDIA ShieldTV is provided only with a 3.10 Linux kernel while the latest stable Linux kernel is 4.4.
Not to mention that the 3.10 kernel is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernel.org/category/releases.html&#34;&gt;not supported any more by the kernel maintainers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this background in mind a major goal of HypriotOS is to provide an operating system that behaves as similar as possible on &lt;strong&gt;different&lt;/strong&gt; IoT devices.
While I know that this might prove to be a difficult task - especially in regards to support for recent Linux kernels - I think it might prove to be a worthwhile effort that provides much value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing a beta version of HypriotOS that supports three different development boards is a first step into that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being just able to flash HypriotOS on a SD card and get going in minutes is one of the basic promises of HypriotOS, so without further ado you can download it here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-rpi/releases&#34;&gt;HypriotOS for the Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-nvidia-shieldtv/releases&#34;&gt;HypriotOS for the NVIDIA ShieldTV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/image-builder-odroid-c1/releases&#34;&gt;HypriotOS for the ODROID C1+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you have a lot of fun trying out what HypriotOS has to offer!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; We changed the default username to &lt;code&gt;pirate&lt;/code&gt; (password &lt;code&gt;hypriot&lt;/code&gt;) and disabled the &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user for security reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By adding support for many more boards we think HypriotOS gets a lot more attractive! What do you think?&lt;br /&gt;
And for which board would you want to see support next?
Help us to get your favourite ARM board supported by HypriotOS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always use the comments below to give us feedback and share it on Twitter or Facebook.
You also might wanna discuss this article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10926502&#34;&gt;HackerNews&lt;/a&gt; or vote it up if you find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Govinda aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_beagile_&#34;&gt;@&lt;em&gt;beagile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HypriotOS: Back Again and Better then Ever</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/hypriotos-back-again-with-docker-on-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/hypriotos-back-again-with-docker-on-arm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Time is running and it is nearly a month since we released our last ARM Docker SD card image for the Raspberry Pi.
Listening to our users and having some ideas of our own we are back again with our latest version of HypriotOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dubbed it &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Jack&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; as every proper software release should have a fitting &lt;a href=&#34;http://royal.pingdom.com/2010/05/27/the-developer-obsession-with-code-names-114-interesting-examples/&#34;&gt;code name&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-changes:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Summary of Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack brings along a host of new features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an upgrade of the Linux kernel from 3.18.8 to &lt;strong&gt;3.18.10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for &lt;a href=&#34;http://openvswitch.org/&#34;&gt;Open vSwitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for &lt;strong&gt;network hotplugging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;out of the box support for &lt;strong&gt;Wifi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support for &lt;strong&gt;Avahi&lt;/strong&gt; (aka Apple Bonjour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more inodes to allow for more files in the filesystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some smaller improvements/additions: fake-hwclock, usbutils, htop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these feature deserve a more thorough explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-vswitch-support:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Open vSwitch support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this cool video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sBy0NVBPc9g&#34;&gt;Running Open vSwitch on Docker&lt;/a&gt; from Dave Tucker as an introduction to Docker and Open vSwitch.
We added the foundation for using Open vSwitch by adding the necessary kernel support into our image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see for yourself by typing the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #272822&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;HypriotOS: root@black-pearl in ~
$ modprobe openvswitch
HypriotOS: root@black-pearl in ~
$ lsmod | grep openvswitch
openvswitch            68194  0
vxlan                  29211  1 openvswitch
gre                     4069  1 openvswitch
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that you still need a working Open vSwitch Docker image that works for ARM.
If nobody else is faster we might provide one soon ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;improved-networking-support:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Improved Networking Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;hotplug:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Hotplug&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the networking with our image a smoother experience we added hotplug support for networking devices.
This allows you to add for instance a USB Wifi Dongle and it will be recognized by your Pi at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check if it worked by using &lt;strong&gt;lsusb&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #272822&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;$ lsusb
Bus 001 Device 002: ID 0424:9514 Standard Microsystems Corp.
Bus 001 Device 001: ID 1d6b:0002 Linux Foundation 2.0 root hub
Bus 001 Device 003: ID 0424:ec00 Standard Microsystems Corp.
Bus 001 Device 004: ID 0bda:8178 Realtek Semiconductor Corp. RTL8192CU 802.11n WLAN Adapter
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wifi:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Wifi&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most asked for features regarding our SD image was the support of Wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get started with Wifi is on Mac with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/flash&#34;&gt;flash script&lt;/a&gt;.
This script does not only allow you to set Wifi configuration but it also allows you to fetch, configure and flash the SD card in one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #272822&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;flash --ssid Your-Wifi-SID --password Your-Wifi-Password http://downloads.hypriot.com/hypriot-rpi-20150329-140334.img.zip
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cannot use our nifty flash tool you have to first boot your Pi with a network cable attached.
Then you can add your Wifi credentials in &lt;code&gt;/boot/occidentalis.txt&lt;/code&gt; as described in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hypriot/flash#occidentalistxt&#34;&gt;Readme&lt;/a&gt; of the flash tool.
Afterwards run &lt;code&gt;occi&lt;/code&gt; at the command line and reboot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After rebooting you should see a wlan-interface with an ip address assigned similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #272822&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;$ ip a
1: lo: &amp;lt;LOOPBACK,UP,LOWER_UP&amp;gt; mtu 65536 qdisc noqueue state UNKNOWN
    link/loopback 00:00:00:00:00:00 brd 00:00:00:00:00:00
    inet 127.0.0.1/8 scope host lo
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
    inet6 ::1/128 scope host
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
2: eth0: &amp;lt;NO-CARRIER,BROADCAST,MULTICAST,UP&amp;gt; mtu 1500 qdisc pfifo_fast state DOWN qlen 1000
    link/ether b8:27:eb:c0:df:1a brd ff:ff:ff:ff:ff:ff
    inet 192.168.178.83/24 brd 192.168.178.255 scope global eth0
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
    inet6 fe80::ba27:ebff:fec0:df1a/64 scope link
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
3: wlan0: &amp;lt;BROADCAST,MULTICAST,UP,LOWER_UP&amp;gt; mtu 1500 qdisc mq state UP qlen 1000
    link/ether e8:4e:06:0b:bf:d8 brd ff:ff:ff:ff:ff:ff
    inet 192.168.178.144/24 brd 192.168.178.255 scope global wlan0
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
    inet6 fe80::ea4e:6ff:fe0b:bfd8/64 scope link
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
4: docker0: &amp;lt;NO-CARRIER,BROADCAST,MULTICAST,UP&amp;gt; mtu 1500 qdisc noqueue state DOWN
    link/ether 56:84:7a:fe:97:99 brd ff:ff:ff:ff:ff:ff
    inet 172.17.42.1/16 scope global docker0
       valid_lft forever preferred_lft forever
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;support-for-avahi-bonjour:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Support for Avahi/Bonjour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major problems after booting your Pi always was how to find out its IP address.
There are many approaches to solve this problem but one of the easiest is with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avahi_(Software&#34;&gt;Avahi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now after booting up our SD card image you can just ssh into your Pi without finding out the IP address first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #272822&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt;$ ssh root@black-pearl.local
root@black-pearl.local&amp;#39;s password:
Linux black-pearl 3.18.10-hypriotos-v7+ #2 SMP PREEMPT Sun Mar 29 13:13:41 UTC 2015 armv7l

The programs included with the Debian GNU/Linux system are free software;
the exact distribution terms for each program are described in the
individual files in /usr/share/doc/*/copyright.

Debian GNU/Linux comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY, to the extent
permitted by applicable law.
Last login: Sun Mar 29 23:49:43 2015 from macbook
HypriotOS: root@black-pearl in ~
$
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;black-pearl&lt;/strong&gt; is the standard hostname your Pi gets after booting with our image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This out of the box experience is once again unfortunately only for Mac users.
Linux and Windows users need to install additional software first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux users need to install the Avahi daemon. For Ubuntu it works like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install avahi-daemon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows users need to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/de/itunes/download/&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; as Bonjour/Avahi comes bundles with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;download:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new image can be downloaded here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://downloads.hypriot.com/hypriot-rpi-20150329-140334.img.zip&#34;&gt;Docker-Pi Image&lt;/a&gt; (~367MB)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://downloads.hypriot.com/hypriot-rpi-20150329-140334.img.zip.sha256&#34;&gt;SHA256 checksum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-get-started:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;How to get started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download our SD card image and flash it on your own SD card. &lt;a href=&#34;http://computers.tutsplus.com/articles/how-to-flash-an-sd-card-for-raspberry-pi--mac-53600&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a short guide on how to do this for Mac, Windows and Linux users. Afterwards insert the SD card in your Raspberry Pi and wait while it boots. The first time will take a little longer as it resizes the file system to its maximum and reboots again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the boot prompt log in with user &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;pi&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; and password &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;raspberry&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; (or with a privileged user &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; and password &amp;ldquo;hypriot&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that is still worth mentioning is that you need special ARM-compatible Docker Images.
&lt;strong&gt;Standard x86-64 Docker Images from the Docker Hub won&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/strong&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s the reason why we&amp;rsquo;ve created a number of ARM compatible Docker Images to get you started. Wether you prefer Java, Python, Node.js or io.js - we have you covered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find these images and more at &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/repos/hypriot/&#34;&gt;our place&lt;/a&gt; on the Docker Hub. After booting our image on your Pi these base images are just a &amp;ldquo;docker pull&amp;rdquo; away. For example &amp;ldquo;docker pull hypriot/rpi-node&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-us-your-feedback:3dc6f6d2f6296024232980f87970ab3c&#34;&gt;Give us your feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we want to make this image even better we really need your feedback. What do you like about our SD card image and what could be made better? And what kind of additional Docker Images would you like to see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us via Twitter, HackerNews or in the comments!
And please share this post with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really would like to see more people using Docker on Raspberries as we think they make a really hot combo:
Low-cost instant access to Docker awesomeness on your Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>